# EVAN REYNOLDS

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER





van.m.reynolds95@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/evanmaxreynolds



github.com/evanreynolds1116

# **ABOUT ME**

After several years of working in the mortgage industry as a loan officer, I decided to follow my passion and pursue a career path in software development by attending Nashville Software School. This field intersects my love for building things, problem solving, and taking on a challenge. I am enthusiastic about being a software developer so that I can thrive in an industry where I can execute my skill base while continuing to thrive and evolve.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript, ReactJS, ChartJS
- Python, Django
- SQL
- Git/GitHub
- JSON Server

#### **PROJECTS**

CONCERT JUNKIE - Front-End Capstone
Concert Junkie is a concert tracker that will
track concerts you've been to by date, tour
name, band(s), venue, and location. It will also
track totals for concerts seen, bands seen,
venues/locations visited, and concerts by year.
Users also have the ability to upload photos
and videos from each concert.

#### **Technology used:**

- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- React, ChartJS, Reactstrap, Reactbootstrap

https://github.com/evanreynolds1116/Capstone-Concert Junkie

<u>MUSIC JUNKIE</u> - Back-End Capstone Music Junkie is a app for users to track their top artists, top songs, favorite albums, and to discover new music,

#### **Technology used:**

• HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Django

#### Front-End Repo:

https://github.com/evanreynolds1116/BackEnd-Capstone-ClientSide

# Back-End Repo:

https://github.com/evanreynolds1116/BackEnd-Capstone-API

# EDUCATION

#### NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Software Developement Apr 2020 - Present

#### **IRVINE VALLEY COLLEGE**

Business Sciences | Aug 2014 - May 2016

# SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Nashville Software School | Apr 2020 - Present

Full time boot camp for full stack software development. Hands on application and experience with:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, Django, and SQL
- Use and creation of multiple API's
- Working with scrum methodology for team projects
- Use of Git and GitHub for version control

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### LICENSED LOAN OFFICER

loanDepot.com - Franklin, TN | May 2017 - Jan 2020

- Receive approximately 10-15+ warm transfers per day from contact center
- Educate applicants on the risks and benefits, as well as the terms of loan products and government regulations
- Obtain relevant information and evaluate applicants financial status, including credit history, debt-to-income ratio, and appraisal reports, to determine recommendation for loan approval
- Maintain current knowledge of all applicable lending regulations, the economy, market rates, vendors, and competitors
- Consistently deliver first-class customer service

#### **CUSTOMER CARE AGENT**

New American Funding - Santa Ana, CA | Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

- Engage in conversation and establish rapport with customers via email and outbound telephone communication
- Inquire and gather information as it relates to a customer's financial situation and financial goals
- Help guide customers and loan officers about next steps for a customer's file

## **COLLECTIONS SPECIALIST**

NexGenMed Solutions - Irvine, CA | Jan 2015 - Mar 2016

- Call insurance adjusters and defense attorneys to negotiate settlements
- Follow up with payers on payment and claim status
- Meet monthly and quarterly collection goals
- Maintain appropriate documentation and records with company database
- Handle large caseload (500+ patient accounts)

#### **DATA ENTRY / BILLING SPECIALIST**

Mesa Pharmacy inc - Irvine, CA | July 2012 - Jan 2015

- Prepare, compile, and sort patient documents for data entry
- Check source documents for accuracy
- Verify data and correct data when necessary
- Obtain further information for incomplete documents
- Transcribe information into required electronic format
- Maintain logbooks or records of activities and tasksComply with data integrity and security policies